<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog>
    <movie>
        <title>Esaretin Bedeli</title>
        <director>Frank Darabont</director>
        <original title>The Shawshank Redemption</original title>
        <category>Drama</category>
        <summary>Two imprisoned men bond over a number of years, finding solace and eventual redemption through acts of common decency.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111161/</url>        
    </movie>

    <movie>
        <title>Baba</title>
        <director>Francis Ford Coppola</director>
        <original title>The Godfather</original title>
        <category>Crime, Drama</category>
        <summary>An organized crime dynasty's aging patriarch transfers control of his clandestine empire to his reluctant son.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0068646/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Kara Şövalye</title>
        <director>Christopher Nolan</director>
        <original title>The Dark Knight</original title>
        <category>Action, Crime, Drama </category>
        <summary>When the menace known as the Joker wreaks havoc and chaos on the people of Gotham, Batman must accept one of the greatest psychological and physical tests of his ability to fight injustice.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0468569/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Başlangıç</title>
        <director>Christopher Nolan</director>
        <original title>Inception</original title>
        <category>Action, Adventure, Sci-Fi</category>
        <summary>A thief who steals corporate secrets through the use of dream-sharing technology is given the inverse task of planting an idea into the mind of a C.E.O.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1375666/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Yüzüklerin Efendisi: Yüzük Kardeşliği</title>
        <director>Peter Jackson</director>
        <original title>The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring</original title>
        <category>Action, Adventure, Drama</category>
        <summary>A meek Hobbit from the Shire and eight companions set out on a journey to destroy the powerful One Ring and save Middle-earth from the Dark Lord Sauron.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120737/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Parazit</title>
        <director>Bong Joon Ho</director>
        <original title>Gisaengchung</original title>
        <category>Comedy, Drama, Thriller</category>
        <summary>Greed and class discrimination threaten the newly formed symbiotic relationship between the wealthy Park family and the destitute Kim clan.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt6751668/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Yıldızlararası</title>
        <director>Christopher Nolan</director>
        <original title>Interstellar</original title>
        <category>Adventure, Drama, Sci-Fi</category>
        <summary>A team of explorers travel through a wormhole in space in an attempt to ensure humanity's survival.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0816692/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Adalet Birliği Zack Snyder</title>
        <director>Zack Snyder</director>
        <original title>Zack Snyder's Justice League</original title>
        <category>Action, Adventure, Fantasy</category>
        <summary>Zack Snyder's definitive director's cut of Justice League. Determined to ensure Superman's ultimate sacrifice was not in vain, Bruce Wayne aligns forces with Diana Prince with plans to recruit a team of metahumans to protect the world from an approaching threat of catastrophic proportions.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt12361974/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Avengers: Sonsuzluk Savaşı</title>
        <director>Steven Knight</director>
        <original title>Avengers: Infinity War</original title>
        <category>Action, Adventure, Sci-Fi</category>
        <summary>The Avengers and their allies must be willing to sacrifice all in an attempt to defeat the powerful Thanos before his blitz of devastation and ruin puts an end to the universe.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt4154756/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Joker</title>
        <director>Todd Phillips</director>
        <original title>Joker</original title>
        <category>Crime, Drama, Thriller</category>
        <summary>In Gotham City, mentally troubled comedian Arthur Fleck is disregarded and mistreated by society. He then embarks on a downward spiral of revolution and bloody crime. This path brings him face-to-face with his alter-ego: the Joker.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt7286456/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Yaratık</title>
        <director>Ridley Scott</director>
        <original title>Alien</original title>
        <category>Horror, Sci-Fi</category>
        <summary>After a space merchant vessel receives an unknown transmission as a distress call, one of the crew is attacked by a mysterious life form and they soon realize that its life cycle has merely begun.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0078748/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Baba</title>
        <director>Florian Zeller</director>
        <original title>The Father</original title>
        <category>Drama</category>
        <summary>A man refuses all assistance from his daughter as he ages. As he tries to make sense of his changing circumstances, he begins to doubt his loved ones, his own mind and even the fabric of his reality.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt10272386/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Soul</title>
        <director>Pete Docter, Kemp Powers</director>
        <original title>Soul</original title>
        <category>Animation, Adventure, Comedy</category>
        <summary>After landing the gig of a lifetime, a New York jazz pianist suddenly finds himself trapped in a strange land between Earth and the afterlife.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2948372/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Blade Runner 2049: Bıçak Sırtı</title>
        <director>Denis Villeneuve</director>
        <original title>Blade Runner 2049</original title>
        <category>Action, Drama, Mystery</category>
        <summary>Young Blade Runner K's discovery of a long-buried secret leads him to track down former Blade Runner Rick Deckard, who's been missing for thirty years.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1856101/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Kaptan Fantastik</title>
        <director>Matt Ross</director>
        <original title>Captain Fantastic</original title>
        <category>Comedy, Drama</category>
        <summary>In the forests of the Pacific Northwest, a father devoted to raising his six kids with a rigorous physical and intellectual education is forced to leave his paradise and enter the world, challenging his idea of what it means to be a parent.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt3553976/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Thor: Ragnarok</title>
        <director>Sydney Newman</director>
        <original title>Thor: Ragnarok</original title>
        <category>Action, Adventure, Comedy</category>
        <summary>Imprisoned on the planet Sakaar, Thor must race against time to return to Asgard and stop Ragnarök, the destruction of his world, at the hands of the powerful and ruthless villain Hela.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt3501632/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Metalin Sesi</title>
        <director>Darius Marder</director>
        <original title>Sound of Metal</original title>
        <category>Drama, Music</category>
        <summary>A heavy-metal drummer's life is thrown into freefall when he begins to lose his hearing.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt5363618/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Şikago Yedilisi'nin Yargılanması</title>
        <director>Aaron Sorkin</director>
        <original title>The Trial of the Chicago 7</original title>
        <category>Drama, History, Thriller</category>
        <summary>The story of 7 people on trial stemming from various charges surrounding the uprising at the 1968 Democratic National Convention in Chicago, Illinois.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1070874/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Druk</title>
        <director>Thomas Vinterberg</director>
        <original title>Druk</original title>
        <category>Comedy, Drama</category>
        <summary>Four friends, all high school teachers, test a theory that they will improve their lives by maintaining a constant level of alcohol in their blood.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt10288566/</url>        
    </movie>
    
    <movie>
        <title>Hiçkimse</title>
        <director>Ilya Naishuller</director>
        <original title>Nobody </original title>
        <category>Action, Crime, Drama</category>
        <summary>A bystander who intervenes to help a woman being harassed by a group of men becomes the target of a vengeful drug lord.
</summary>
        <url>https://www.imdb.com/title/tt7888964/</url>        
    </movie>

</catalog>